Lumos Maxima.
[咒语] 鼓德冒斯 玛西姆
Lumos Maxima!
《哈利波特与阿兹卡班囚徒》
Harry. Harry.
哈利…哈利…
Harry, open the door.
哈利…快开门
Marge. How lovely to see...
噢.玛姬.见到你真高兴…
Uncle Vernon, I need you to sign this form.
弗农姨夫.请在这张表上签个字
What is it?
这是什么？
Nothing. School stuff.
没什么.学校里的
Later perhaps, if you behave.
你要是守规矩.我就签
I will if she does.
只要玛姬不忘守规矩
- Oh, you're still here, are you? - Yes.
- 喔…你还住在这儿.是吗？ - 当然
Don't say yes in that ungrateful way.
听听.“当然”.你这没良心的东西
Damn good of my brother to keep you.
我弟弟心肠好收留你
He'd have been straight to an orphanage if he'd been dumped on my doorstep.
要是换了我 我就把他送到孤儿院去
Is that my Dudders? Is that my little neffy-pooh?
哦.那是我的小达力.是我的宝贝小侄子
Give us a kiss. Come on. Up, up.
嗯.来亲一个
Take Marge's suitcase upstairs.
把玛姬的行李搬上楼
Okay.
好吧
Finish that off for Mommy. Good boy, Rippy-pooh.
来.帮妈妈吃完吧 我的宝贝儿.好乖乖
- Can I tempt you, Marge? - Just a small one.
- 来杯酒吗？.玛姬 - 就一小杯
Excellent nosh, Petunia.
点心棒极了.佩妮
A bit more.
再倒一点
Usually just a fry-up for me, what with 12 dogs.
我要照顾几条小狗… 吃得也就马虎了
Just a bit more. That's a boy.
再来点.这就对了
You wanna try a little drop of brandy?
啊.你想尝一小口白兰地吗？
A little drop of brandy-brandy windy-wandy for Rippy-pippy-pooh?
我的乖乖小宝贝.它的味道棒极了
What are you smirking at?
你傻笑什么啊？
Where did you send the boy, Vernon?
你送他去哪儿来着？
St. Brutus'. It's a fine institution for hopeless cases.
圣布鲁斯 不可救药的孩子去那个学校正合适
Do they use a cane at St. Brutus', boy?
那儿不规矩要被藤条抽吗？
Oh, yeah.
喔.是啊！
Yeah. I've been beaten loads of times.
我都被抽了好几回了
Excellent. I won't have this namby-pamby...
好极了 我可不爱听那些废话
...wishy-washy nonsense about not beating people who deserve it.
说什么别打那些该打的人
You mustn't blame yourself about how this one turned out.
也不要为这不争气的小子太自责.弗农
It's all to do with blood. Bad blood will out.
这是遗传的 孽种的缺陷是藏不住的
What is it the boy's father did, Petunia?
这小子的父亲是干嘛的？
Nothing. He didn't work. He was unemployed.
不干嘛.他…他没有工作 被辞退了
- And a drunk too, no doubt? - That's a lie.
- 一定还是个酒鬼 - 胡说八道
- What did you say? - My dad wasn't a drunk.
- 你说什么？ - 我爸爸不是酒鬼
Don't worry. Don't fuss, Petunia. I have a very firm grip.
没关系.别大惊小怪 是我握得太紧了
I think it's time you went to bed.
你该上床睡觉了
Quiet, Vernon. You, clean it up.
别吵 你…弄干净
Actually, it's nothing to do with the father.
其实 跟他父亲没关系
It's all to do with the mother. You see it all the time with dogs.
要怪就怪他母亲 反正狗就是这样的
If something's wrong with the bitch, then something's wrong with the pup.
要是母狗出了问题 那么生出来的小狗就一定有问题
Shut up! Shut up!
你闭嘴.给我闭嘴…
Right.
好吧
Let me tell you...
我告诉你们吧.你…
Vernon!
弗农
Vernon! Vernon, do something!
弗农…快点想办法
Stop!
停下
I've got you, Marge. I've got you.
我抓住你了.玛姬.抓住了
- Hold on, hold on. - Get off.
- 你不能放手 - 滚开
- Don't you dare! - Sorry.
- 别放手！ - 对不起
Oh, Vernon.
弗农
Oh, God.
噢.上帝！
Marge!
玛姬
Please!
玛姬…
Marge!
回来…
Come back!
回来
You bring her back! You bring her back now.
你把她弄回来.快把她弄回来
- You put her right! - No. She deserved what she got.
- 恢复原状 - 不.她这是活该！
- Keep away from me. - You can't do magic outside school.
- 闪开.离我远点 - 你在校外不能使魔法
- Yeah? Try me. - They won't let you back now.
- 是吗？那就试试 - 他们不会让你回去了
You've nowhere to go.
你没地方去了
I don't care. Anywhere is better than here.
我不在乎.哪儿都比这儿好
"Welcome to the Knight Bus...
欢迎乘坐骑士大巴
...emergency transport for the stranded witch or wizard.
这是应急车 运送陷入困境的魔法师
My name is Stan Shunpike, and I will be your conductor for this evening."
我叫斯坦·桑帕克 今晚我将做你的售票员
What you doing down there?
你坐在地上干嘛？
- I fell over. - What you fell over for?
- 我摔倒了 - 没事干嘛要摔倒？
- I didn't do it on purpose. - Well, come on, then.
- 我又不是故意的 - 那就起来吧
Let's not wait for the grass to grow.
别在这儿瞎耽误工夫了
- What you looking at? - Nothing.
- 你在看什么？ - 没什么
Well, come on, then. In.
那就快上车吧
No, no, no. I'll get this. You get in.
呃.不不不.我搬行李.你上车
Come on.
唉
Come on. Move on, move on.
快点.往前.往前.往前…
- Take her away, Ern. - Yeah, take it away, Ernie.
- 开车吧.厄恩 - 对.开车吧.厄恩
It's going to be a bumpy ride.
这将是一次颠簸的旅程
- What did you say your name was? - I didn't.
- 刚才你说你叫什么名字？ - 我没说
- Whereabouts are you headed? - The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London.
- 你要去哪儿？ - 破釜酒吧.在伦敦
You hear that? "The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London."
听见了吗.厄恩？ 破釜酒吧.在伦敦
The Leaky Cauldron. If you have pea soup...
破釜酒吧.若给你豌豆汤
...make sure you eat it before it eats you.
一定要在它吃掉你之前吃掉它
- But the Muggles. Can't they see us? - Muggles?
- 那些麻瓜…他们看不见我们吗？ - 麻瓜？
They don't see nothing, do they?
他们什么都看不见.对吗？
No, but if you jab them with a fork, they feel.
对.不过用叉子猛戳 他们有感觉
Ernie, little old lady at 12 o'clock!
十二点方向有个老太太
Ten, nine, eight...
十.九.八…
...seven, six, five...
七.六.五.四…
...four, three, three and a half...
三.二点五…
...two, one and three quarters.
二.一.零点七…
Yes!
冲啊！
Who is that?
他是谁？
That man.
这个人
Who is that?
他是谁？
Who is...
他是…
That is Sirius Black, that is.
小天狼星布莱克
Don't tell me you've never been hearing of Sirius Black.
你不会… 没听过小天狼星布莱克吧
He's a murderer.
他是杀人犯
Got himself locked up in Azkaban for it.
因为杀人被关进了阿兹卡班监狱
- How did he escape? - Well, that's the question, isn't it?
- 他怎么逃跑的？ - 噢.这的确让人费解
He's the first one that done it.
他是第一个成功越狱的
He was a big supporter of...
他最最支持的就是
...You-Know-Who.
神秘人…
I reckon you've heard of him.
你一定听说过他
Yeah.
是啊
Him I've heard of.
我听说过
Ernie, two double-deckers at 12 o'clock.
十二点方向有两辆双层巴士
They're getting closer, Ernie.
离我们越来越近了
Ernie, they're right on top of us!
就在我们前面
Mind your head.
小心你的头
Hey, guys? Guys?
各位.各位？
Why the long faces?
干嘛拉长脸？
Yeah, yeah. Nearly there. Nearly there.
耶.耶.快到了…快到了…快到了
- The Leaky Cauldron. - Next stop, Knockturn Alley.
- 破釜酒吧到了 - 下一站.翻倒巷
Mr. Potter, at last.
哈利波特先生.我们又见面了
- Take it away, Ern. - Yeah, take it away, Ernie!
- 开车吧.厄恩 - 开车
Room 11.
十一号房间
Hedwig.
海德薇
Right smart bird you got there, Mr. Potter.
你的猫头鹰真聪明.波特先生
He arrived here just five minutes before yourself.
他比你早五分钟飞到这儿来
As Minister for Magic, it is my duty to inform you, Mr. Potter...
身为魔法部部长.我有责任告诉你 波特先生
...earlier this evening your uncle's sister was located...
今晚早些时候… 有人看见你姨夫的姐姐
...a little south of Sheffield, circling a chimney stack.
在谢菲尔的南边围着一根烟囱打转
The Accidental Magic Reversal Department was dispatched immediately.
部里当即派遣逆转偶发事件司前去现场处理
She has been properly punctured and her memory modified.
她已经被恢复原状.那段记忆也被抹去
She will have no recollection of the incident whatsoever.
那件事.她一点都不会记起. 全都不记得了
So that's that...
所以圆满解决
...and no harm done.
而且丝毫没有损害
Pea soup?
豌豆汤？
No, thank you.
不用.谢谢
- Minister? - Yes?
- 部长先生？ - 什么？
- I don't understand. - Understand?
- 我不明白 - 不明白？
I broke the law. Underage wizards can't use magic at home.
我违法了.我是不能在家中使用魔法的
Come now. The Ministry doesn't send people to Azkaban...
得了.不会因为有人把姑妈吹成气球
...for blowing up their aunts.
就把他关进阿兹卡班
On the other hand, running away like that, given the state of things...
话说回来.像你那么离家出走 在目前的情况下
...was very, very irresponsible.
是非常非常不负责任的
- "The state of things," sir? - We have a killer on the loose.
- 目前的情况指什么？ - 有个杀人犯越狱了
Sirius Black, you mean?
小天狼星布莱克？
But what's he got to do with me?
他跟我有什么关系？
Nothing, of course. You're safe. And that's what matters.
当然没有关系 你很安全.这才是最重要的
And tomorrow you'll be on your way back to Hogwarts.
明天你又将启程回霍格沃茨
These are your new schoolbooks. I took the liberty...
呃.这些是你的新课本 我自作主张
...of having them brought here. Now Tom will show you to your room.
把它们一起带来交给你； 现在.汤姆会带你去房间
Hedwig.
海德薇
Oh, by the way, Harry. Whilst you're here, it would be best if you didn't...
呃.随便说一句.哈利. 你在这儿的时候.最好不要到处…
...wander.
乱跑
Right! You gonna move that bus or what?
喂！到底你要不要开走？
《妖怪们的妖怪书》
Housekeeping.
客房服务
I'll come back later.
我一会儿再来
I'm warning you, Hermione.
我警告你,赫敏
Keep that beast away from Scabbers, or I'll turn it into a tea cozy.
让那畜生离斑斑远一点 不然我就把他变成茶壶保暖套
It's a cat, Ronald. What do you expect?
他是只猫,罗恩
- It's in his nature. - A cat? Is that what they told you?
- 猫天生就这样 - 这叫猫.你管这叫猫？
- Looks like a pig with hair. - That's rich...
- 我看着就像一头长毛猪 - 真可笑
...coming from the owner of that smelly old shoe brush.
自己的臭耗子像鞋刷还说别人
Crookshanks, just ignore the mean little boy.
没关系.克鲁克山 不用理那坏小子
Harry.
哈利！
- Egypt. What's it like? - Brilliant. Loads of old stuff...
- 埃及？那儿什么样？ - 有好多东西
...like mummies, tombs, even Scabbers enjoyed himself.
木乃伊、古墓… 斑斑也玩得很开心
- Egyptians used to worship cats. - Along with the dung beetle.
- 以前埃及人崇拜猫 - 对.还崇拜屎壳郎咧
- Not flashing that clipping again? - I haven't shown anyone.
- 又在显摆你的剪报了.罗恩 - 我没给人看过
No, not a soul. Not unless you count Tom.
噢.还说没有人呢.除非你忘了汤姆
- The day maid. - Night maid.
- 早班女佣 - 夜班女佣
- Cook. - The bloke who fixed the toilet.
- 厨师 - 修马桶的那个人
- Harry. - Mrs. Weasley.
- 哈利 - 韦斯莱太太
- Good to see you, dear. - Good to see you.
- 见到你真高兴 - 我也是
- Got everything? - Yes.
- 需要的都带了吗？ - 带了
- Yes? All your books? - It's all upstairs.
- 是吗？所有的书… - 都在楼上
- Your clothes? - Everything.
- 所有的衣服？ - 一切都在
- Good boy. - Thank you.
- 好孩子 - 谢谢
- Harry Potter. - Mr. Weasley.
- 哈里波特 - 韦斯莱先生
- Harry, wonder if I might have a word? - Yeah, sure.
- 哈利.能跟你说句话吗？ - 好啊
- Hermione. - Good morning, Mr. Weasley.
- 赫敏 - 早.韦斯莱先生
- Looking forward to a new term? - Yeah. It should be great.
- 期待着新学期？ - 是呀.一定带劲
Harry, some within the Ministry would strongly discourage me...
哈利.魔法部里有些人… 会强烈反对
...from divulging what I'm about to reveal to you.
我把接下来要说的这件事向你透露
But I think that you need to know the facts.
可是我认为你应该了解真相
You are in danger.
你现在有危险
Grave danger.
很大的危险
Has this anything to do with Sirius Black, sir?
这跟小天狼星布莱克有关吗？
What do you know about Sirius Black, Harry?
布莱克的事你知道多少？
- Only that he's escaped from Azkaban. - Do you know why?
- 只知道他越狱了 - 知道为什么？
Thirteen years ago, when you stopped...
十三年前.当你阻止了…
- Voldemort. - Don't say his name.
- 伏地魔 - 别提他的名字
Sorry.
对不起
When you stopped You-Know-Who...
当你阻止了… 神秘人
...Black lost everything.
布莱克就失去了一切
But to this day, he still remains a faithful servant.
直到今天. 他仍然是一个忠实的仆人
And in his mind...
所以.在他的眼里
...you are the only thing that stands in the way...
你是中间唯一挡道的 阻碍了…
...of You-Know-Who returning to power.
神秘人…卷土重来
And that is why...
就因为这个.他才会
...he has escaped from Azkaban.
从阿兹卡班逃出来
To find you.
来找你
And kill me.
然后杀我
Harry, swear to me that whatever you might hear...
我要你向我发誓.无论你听到什么
...you won't go looking for Black.
你都不会去找布莱克
Mr. Weasley...
韦斯莱先生
...why would I go looking for someone who wants to kill me?
我为什么要去找一个想要杀我的人呢？
Quick. Quick.
快点！快点！
Ron, Ron!
罗恩…
Oh, for goodness' sake!
我的天啊
Don't lose him!
不要忘了他
I didn't mean to blow her up. I just...
我没想把她吹大 我…
- I lost control. - Brilliant.
- 只是失控了 - 帅呆了
Honestly, Ron, it's not funny. Harry was lucky not to be expelled.
罗恩.这可不好玩 幸好哈利没被开除
I was lucky not to be arrested.
应该说幸好我没被逮捕
I still think it was brilliant.
我还是觉得帅呆了
Come on. Everywhere else is full.
来吧.别处坐满了
Who do you think that is?
那人是谁啊？
225 - Professor R.J. Lupin. - Do you know everything?
- l.J.卢平教授 - 你什么都知道
How is it she knows everything?
她怎么什么都知道？
- It's on his suitcase, Ronald. - Oh.
- 他的箱子上写着呢 - 哦
- Do you think he's really asleep? - Seems to be. Why?
- 他真的睡着了吗？ - 应该是吧.怎么？
I gotta tell you something.
跟你们说件事儿
Let me get this straight. Sirius Black escaped from Azkaban...
先让我们先搞清楚 布莱克从阿兹卡班逃出来
- ...to come after you? - Yeah.
- 是为了追杀你 - 对
But they'll catch Black, won't they?
他一定会被抓住的
- I mean, everyone's looking for him. - Sure.
- 所有人都在找他 - 当然
Except no one's ever broken out of Azkaban before...
只是… 以前没有人能从阿兹卡班逃出来
- ...and he's a murderous, raving lunatic. - Thanks, Ron.
- 再说.他是杀人成性的疯子 - 多谢.罗恩
Why are we stopping?
怎么停了？
We can't be there yet.
还没到呢
What's going on?
怎么回事啊？
I don't know. Maybe we've broken down.
不知道.也许是故障
Ouch, Ron. That was my foot.
噢.你踩我脚了
There's something moving out there.
外面有东西在动
I think someone's coming aboard.
我想…有人要上车
Bloody hell! What's happening?
活见鬼.怎么回事呀？
Harry.
哈利！
Harry, are you all right?
哈利.你没事吧？
Thank you.
谢谢
Here, eat this. It'll help.
给.吃这个.会管用的
It's all right. It's chocolate.
没事儿.是巧克力
What was that thing that came?
刚…刚才那个是什么?
It was a dementor. One of the guards of Azkaban. It's gone now.
是个摄魂怪.阿兹卡班的看守之一
It was searching the train for Sirius Black.
他在车厢里找小天狼星布莱克
If you'll excuse me, I need to have a little word with the driver.
我失陪一会儿 得去跟司机说句话
Eat. You'll feel better.
吃吧.会好些
What happened to me?
我怎么了？
Well, you sort of went rigid.
你全身僵硬
We thought maybe you were having a fit or something.
我们还以为你癫痫病发作了
And did either of you two...
呃…你们是不是也…
...you know...
失去…
- ...pass out? - No.
- 知觉了？ - 没有
I felt weird, though.
可感觉怪怪的
Like I'd never be cheerful again.
好像再也没了快乐
But someone was screaming.
我听见尖叫
A woman.
是个女人
No one was screaming, Harry.
没有人尖叫.哈利
（霍格莫德）
Welcome! Welcome to another year at Hogwarts.
欢迎来霍格沃茨度过新学年
267 Now, I'd like to say a few words...
我有几句话要说…
...before we all become too befuddled by our excellent feast.
趁大家还没被这美味大餐弄得迷迷糊糊的
First, I'm pleased to welcome Professor R.J. Lupin...
首先.欢迎新来的教授l.J.卢平
...who's kindly consented to fill the post...
他欣然同意填补空缺
...of Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
教授黑魔法防御术这门课程
Good luck, professor.
祝你好运.教授
Of course. That's why he knew to give you the chocolate, Harry.
怪不得他知道该给你吃巧克力
Potter. Is it true you fainted?
嘿.波特 听说你昏过去了？
- I mean, you actually fainted? - Shove off, Malfoy.
- 你是真的昏过去了？ - 你滚开.马尔福
- How did he find out? - Just forget it.
- 他怎么会知道的？ - 我哪知道
Our Care of Magical Creatures teacher...
凯特尔·博恩教授多年来 一直教授保护神奇生物课
...has decided to retire...
他已经决定退休
...in order to spend more time with his remaining limbs.
以便有更多的时间来照料残留的肢体
Fortunately, I'm delighted to announce...
所幸的是.我荣幸地宣布
...that his place will be taken by none other...
已有人接替他的职位.而且不是别人
...than our own Rubeus Hagrid.
正是我们的鲁伯·海格
Finally, on a more disquieting note...
最后.有件更为严肃的事…
...at the request of the Ministry of Magic...
在魔法部的要求下…
...Hogwarts will, until further notice, play host to the dementors of Azkaban...
霍格沃茨将由一些来自 阿兹卡班的摄魂怪看守
...until such a time as Sirius Black is captured.
直到小天狼星布莱克被捕的那一刻
The dementors will be stationed at every entrance to the grounds.
摄魂怪将驻守在学校的每一个入口
Now whilst I've been assured...
虽然我已得到保证
...that their presence will not disrupt our day-to-day activities...
它们的出现不会打乱我们的日常生活
...a word of caution.
但我提醒诸位
Dementors are vicious creatures. They'll not distinguish...
它们是凶残的生物.不会区分
...between the one they hunt and the one who gets in their way.
它们要追捕的人和挡它们道的人
Therefore, I must warn each and every one of you...
因此我必须警告在座的每个人
...to give them no reason to harm you.
别让它们找到理由伤害你们
It is not in the nature of a dementor to be forgiving.
那些摄魂怪天生就不知道什么是原谅
But you know, happiness can be found...
可我们.总能找到快乐
...even in the darkest of times...
甚至在最黑暗的时期
...if one only remembers to turn on the light.
只要你们记得…把灯点亮
Fortuna Major.
[开门咒] 否琼勒米杰
Here, listen. She just won't let me in.
嘿.听着.她不让我进去
- Fortuna Major. - No, no. Wait, wait.
- [开门咒] 否琼勒米杰 - 哦…不…等等…等等
Watch this.
瞧这个
- Amazing. Just with my voice. - Fortuna Major.
- 了不起.我的歌喉震碎的 - [开门咒] 否琼勒米杰
- Yes, all right. Go in. - Thank you.
- 那好吧.进来吧 - 谢谢
Still doing that after three years.
天哪.都三年了.她还在吊嗓子
- She can't even sing. - Exactly.
- 她五音不全 - 的确太离谱了
- Hey, man. - Hey, man.
- 嘿.朋友 - 呃.呃
- Oh, God. - That's awful.
- 天啊 - 太真可怕了
Green. That's a monkey.
嘿.那是绿的.那是猴子
- What is that? - You call that a monkey?
- 什么呀？ - 那他也是猴子？
Do not give him one again.
别再给他糖了
Hey, Neville, try an elephant.
嘿.纳威.尝尝大象
- Ron, catch. - I will.
- 罗恩.接着 - 我会的
I think we have a winner.
够厉害的
- Oh, don't try one of them. - Oh, no.
- 不…别尝那个 - 嗬.那是什么
Look at him. His face.
快瞧瞧他的脸
Welcome, my children.
欢迎我的孩子们
In this room, you shall explore the noble art of Divination.
在我这儿 你们将探究占卜.几种卓越的法术
In this room, you shall discover if you possess the Sight.
在我这儿 你们将知道自己是否具备视野
Hello. I am Professor Trelawney.
我…我是教授特里劳妮
Together we shall cast ourselves into the future.
在这里.我们将一起学习如何预知未来
This term, we'll focus on Tasseomancy, the art of reading tea leaves.
这学期.我们的重点是探索麦迪 解读茶叶术
So please, take the cup of the person sitting opposite you.
现在请和坐在你对面的同学交换茶杯
What do you see?
看见什么啦？
The truth lies buried like a sentence deep within a book, waiting to be read.
真相暗藏着 犹如藏在书中的句子.等人来解读
But first, you must broaden your minds.
可首先必须开阔思路
- First, you must look beyond. - What a load of rubbish.
- 首先眼光必须放远 - 简直一派胡言
- Where did you come from? - Me?
- 你哪儿冒出来的？ - 我？
- I've been here all this time. - You, boy...
- 一直都在 - 我说孩子
Is your grandmother quite well?
你奶奶身体好吗？
I think so.
还好吧
I wouldn't be so sure of that. Give me the cup.
依我看不一定  杯子拿来
Pity.
遗憾
Broaden your minds.
开阔思路
Your aura is pulsing, dear. Are you in the beyond?
你的光环经过死神 你是不在彼岸
- I think you are. - Sure.
- 我想是的 - 当然
Look at the cup. Tell me what you see.
看着杯子.说你看见了
Yeah.
好.哈利
Harry's got sort of a wonky cross. That's trials and suffering.
有一个歪十字架 那代表考验和苦难
And that there could be the sun and that's happiness.
这儿.另外.可能是太阳 那代表快乐
So...
所以…
...you're gonna suffer, but you're gonna be happy about it.
你会受苦 可同时你会很快乐
Give me the cup.
杯子拿来
Oh, my dear boy.
亲爱的孩子
My dear...
亲爱的
...you have the Grim.
你有…不详
The Grin? What's the Grin?
不强？什么叫不强？
Not the Grin, you idiot. The Grim.
不是不强.白痴.是不详
"Taking form of a giant spectral dog.
外形是一条凶恶的大狗
It's among the darkest omens in our world.
是我们世界最恶毒的征兆
It's an omen...
它预示着
...of death."
死亡
You don't think that Grim thing's got anything to do with Sirius Black?
你们说那个不祥和小天狼星布莱克有关吗？
Oh, honestly, Ron. If you ask me, Divination's a woolly discipline.
说实话.罗恩.我看… 占卜学实在经不起推敲
Now, Ancient Runes, that's a fascinating subject.
其实.古代儒尼文 那门课才真有意思呢
Ancient Runes? Exactly how many classes are you taking?
古代儒尼文？ 你这学期你要学几门课？
A fair few.
好几门吧
Hang on. That's not possible.
呃.等等.这不可能
Ancient Runes is in the same time as Divination.
古代儒尼文和占卜课是同一时间
You have to be in two classes at once.
你得同一时间上两门课
Don't be silly. How could anyone be in two classes at once?
别傻了 没人能同一时间上两门课
"Broaden your minds. Use your Inner Eye to see the future."
开阔你们的思路 用你们的天目看未来
That's it. Come on, now. Come closer. Less talking, if you don't mind.
好了.都过来.都走近些 请不要讲话
I got a real treat for you today.
今天让你们一饱眼福
A great lesson. So follow me.
精彩的一课.请跟我来
Right, you lot. Less chattering. Form a group over there.
好了.同学们.请安静 在哪儿站成一组
And open your books to page 49.
把书翻到49页
Exactly how do we do that?
可这书怎么打开呀？
Just stroke the spine, of course. Goodness me.
当然得先把书捋一捋了 真是的
- Don't be such a wimp, Longbottom. - I'm okay. Okay.
- 别这么没用.隆巴顿 - 我没事
- I think they're funny. - Oh, yeah. Terribly funny.
- 这些书真滑稽 - 噢.是呀.滑稽死了.设计巧妙
Witty. God, this place has gone to the dogs.
这学校再这样下去就完了
Wait until Father hears Dumbledore's got this oaf teaching classes.
我爸要知道邓布利多 让这混蛋教课就热闹了
Shut up, Malfoy.
你闭嘴.马尔福
Dementor! Dementor!
摄魂怪…摄魂怪…
- Just ignore him. - You're supposed to stroke it.
- 别管他 - 你应该捋一捋
Yeah.
是
Isn't he beautiful?
他是不是很漂亮？
Say hello to Buckbeak.
来认识一下巴克比克
Hagrid, exactly what is that?
海格.这是什么呀？
That, Ron, is a hippogriff.
是鹰头马身有翼兽
First thing you wanna know is they're very proud creatures.
现在你们要了解的是 它们非常傲慢
Very easily offended. You do not want to insult a hippogriff.
脾气可不好惹 千万别羞辱鹰头马身兽
It may be the last thing you ever do.
弄不好会搭上你的性命
Now, who'd like to come and say hello?
现在.谁来跟它打个招呼？
Well done, Harry. Well done.
好样的.哈利
Come on now.
来吧
Now...
好了
...you have to let him make the first move. It's only polite. So...
你得尊重礼让.这是礼貌
...step up. Give him a nice bow.
所以.走上前.向它鞠个躬
Then you wait and see if he bows back.
然后等着.看它是不是还礼
If he does, you can go and touch him.
它还礼.你才能摸它
If not... Well, we'll get to that later.
不然的话… 好吧好吧好吧.过会儿再说
Just make your bow.
现在向它鞠躬
Nice and low.
再低些
Back off, Harry. Back off.
往后退.哈利.退后
Keep still.
别乱动
Well done, Harry. Well done. Here, you big brute, you.
干得好.哈利.干得好 嘿.你个大家伙
Right. I think you can go and pat him now.
现在.你可以上去拍拍它
Go on. Don't be shy.
去吧.别害羞
Nice and slow, now. Nice and slow. Slow.
要轻轻地.慢慢地.慢慢地
Not so fast, Harry.
别那么快.哈利
Slow down, Harry. That's it...
慢点.哈利
Nice and slow. Now let him come to you.
轻轻地.我慢慢的让它靠近
Slowly, now, slowly, slowly...
轻轻的…慢慢的…
That's it...
再慢点…
Yes!
对了！
Well done! Well done, Harry, well done!
干得好.干得好.哈利！
Does he get to fly?
干得好
- I think he may let you ride him now. - What?
- 现在它愿意让你骑 - 什么？
- Come on. - Hey, hey, hey!
- 来吧 - 嘿！嘿！嘿！
Put you over here, just behind the wing joint.
把你抱上去.坐在翅膀关节的后面
Don't pull out any of his feathers, because he won't thank you for that.
别拔它的羽毛.它会谢你的
Well done, Harry, and well done, Buckbeak.
干得好.哈利
That was wicked, Harry!
干得好
Oh, please.
噢.得了！
Well done, well done.
好极了
- How am I doing me first day? - Brilliant, professor.
- 我今天的课怎么样？ - 一级棒.教授
You're not dangerous at all, are you, you great ugly brute!
你根本就不危险.对吗？ 丑八怪！大怪兽！
Malfoy, no...
不
No!
不要.马尔福！
Buckbeak!
巴克比克
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
哇！哇！哇！
Whoa! Buckbeak!
巴克比克
Away, you silly creature...
你这笨畜生
- It's killed me! - Calm down. It's just a scratch!
- 咹.它杀了我.它杀了我 - 冷静些.只是皮肉伤
Hagrid!
海格
- He has to be taken to the hospital. - I'm the teacher. I'll do it.
- 必须立刻送他去医院 - 我是老师.我来送
- You're gonna regret this. - Class dismissed!
- 我…我…会让你后悔的… - 现在下课
You and your bloody chicken!
你和你那该死的野鸡
Does it hurt terribly, Draco?
是不是很疼.马尔福？
It comes and it goes. Still, I consider myself lucky.
时好时坏.不过.我还是命大
Madam Pomfrey said another minute and I could've lost my arm.
庞弗雷夫人说再拖上一两分钟 胳膊就完了
- I can't do homework for weeks. - Listen to the idiot.
- 那我就几星期不能做功课了 - 听听这白痴说的
- He's really laying it on thick, isn't he? - At least Hagrid didn't get fired.
- 他还真越说越离谱了 - 至少海格没被开除
I hear Draco's father's furious. We haven't heard the end of this.
可我听说马尔福的爸爸很凶啊 这事儿还没完呢
- He's been sighted! - Who?
- 有人看见他了！看见他了！ - 谁？
Sirius Black!
小天狼星布莱克
Dufftown? That's not far from here.
达福镇？离这儿可不远
You don't think he'd come to Hogwarts, do you?
他不会来霍格沃茨吧？
- With dementors at every entrance? - Dementors?
- 入口有摄魂怪把守 - 摄魂怪？
He slipped past them once. Who's to say he won't do it again?
他们已经让它溜了一次 谁敢保证不会有第二次
That's right. Black could be anywhere. It's like trying to catch smoke.
说得对.他神出鬼没的 抓他就像抓烟雾
Like trying to catch smoke with your bare hands.
用你的手抓烟雾
Intriguing, isn't it?
是不是很奇妙？
Would anyone like to venture a guess...
有哪位同学能猜一下
...as to what is inside?
里面是什么？
- That's a boggart, that is. - Very good, Mr. Thomas.
- 是一个博格特？ - 很好.托马斯先生
Now, can anybody tell me what a boggart looks like?
那谁能告诉我 博格特长什么样？
- No one knows. - When did she get here?
- 没人知道 - 它几时来的？
Boggarts are shape-shifters.
博格特会变形
They take the shape of whatever a person fears the most.
见到它的人,心里最怕什么 它就会变成什么
- That's what makes them so... - So terrifying, yes, yes, yes...
- 所以它们是那么的… - 那么的恐怖…
Luckily, a very simple charm exists to repel a boggart.
所幸的是 有一个很简单的咒语就能击退博格特
Let's practice it now. Without wands, please.
现在来练习 请先别用魔杖
After me. Riddikulus!
跟我念.瑞地肯尤拉斯
- Riddikulus! - Very good.
- 瑞地肯尤拉 - 非常好
A little louder and very clear. Listen:
再响亮些.要说清楚
- Riddikulus! - Riddikulus!
- 听好.瑞地肯尤拉斯 - 瑞地肯尤拉斯
- This class is ridiculous. - Very good.
- 听得像溜得快拉屎 - 好了
So much for the easy part. You see, the incantation alone is not enough.
我们就先练到这儿吧 要知道单靠咒语是不够的
What really finishes a boggart is laughter.
真正能把博格特击垮的是… 大笑
You need to force it to assume a shape you find truly amusing.
你们得强迫它变成你们认为… 真正可笑的形象
Let me explain. Neville, would you join me, please?
我来解释 纳威.请你过来.好吗？
Come on, don't be shy. Come on.
来吧.别害羞.来吧
Come on.
来吧
Hello. Neville, what frightens you most of all?
哈啰.纳威 你最害怕的是什么？
Professor Snape.
斯内普教授
- Sorry? - Professor Snape.
- 什么？ - 斯内普教授
Professor Snape. Yes, frightens all.
斯内普教授？是的.都怕他
- You live with your grandmother. - I don't want it to turn into her, either.
- 你是和奶奶一块儿住的？ - 是的.我也不想博格特变成她的样子
No...
不会的
...it won't. I want you to picture her clothes.
现在想想奶奶是怎么穿戴的
Only her clothes, very clearly, in your mind.
只想她的穿戴.而且要想清楚
- She carries a red handbag... - We don't need to hear.
- 她拿一只红色的手袋 - 不需要说出来
As long as you see it, we'll see it. Now, when I open that wardrobe...
你只要你看见.我们就能看 我打开衣柜的时候
...here's what I want you to do. Excuse me.
我会要你这么做…
Imagine Professor Snape in your grandmother's clothes.
想想斯内普教授穿着你奶奶的衣服
Can you do that?
能做到吗？
Yes. Wand at the ready.
开始.魔杖准备
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Think, Neville, think.
快想.纳威.快想
Riddikulus!
瑞地肯尤拉斯
Wonderful, Neville, wonderful! Incredible! Okay...
好极了.纳威.好极了 不可思议
...to the back, Neville. Everyone, form a line...
都往后退.大家排好队
Form a line!
排好队
I want everyone to picture the thing they fear the very most...
我要每个人都想出自己最害怕的东西
...and turn it into something funny.
然后把它变得很可笑
Next! Ron!
下一个.罗恩
Concentrate. Face your fear. Be brave!
集中思想.面对恐惧.勇敢些
Wand at the ready, Ron.
魔杖准备
Riddikulus!
瑞地肯尤拉斯
Yes!You see?
好极了.瞧见了
Very good, very good!
非常好.非常好太精采了.很好
Marvelous! Absolutely, very, very enjoyable! Parvati! Next!
这实在是让人乐不可支 帕瓦蒂.快上
Show us what you see.
你看见了什么？
Keep your nerve. Steady.
别慌.千万别慌
Riddikulus!
瑞地肯尤拉斯
And next! Step up, step up!
下一个.往前走….往前走…
Wonderful, wonderful!
好极了！好极了！
Here!
走！
Riddikulus!
瑞地肯尤拉斯
Right. Sorry about that. That's enough for today.
嗯.好吧.非常抱歉.今天就练到这儿吧
Collect your books from the back.
都去后面拿回自己的书
That's the end of the lesson. Thank you! Sorry!
课就上到这儿.谢谢
Sorry, you can have too much of a good thing.
抱歉. 好了.走吧.别玩物丧志
Remember, these visits to Hogsmeade village are a privilege.
现在记住 去霍格莫德村应该是一种荣幸
Should your behavior reflect poorly on the school...
如果有谁在学校的表现欠佳.那么
...that privilege shall not be extended again.
就不再享受这份特殊的待遇
No permission form signed, no visiting the village.
座位表上没签字.就不能去那个村
That's the rule, Potter.
这是规定
Those with permission, follow me. Those without, stay put.
表上签了字的跟我来 没签字的别跟来
I thought if you signed it, then I could...
教授.我想.如果你签了字 那我就能去了
I can't. Only a parent or a guardian can sign.
我不能签 只有家长或监护人可以签
Since I am neither, it would be inappropriate.
我都不是.那就不能签
I'm sorry, Potter. That's my final word.
对不起.波特.我的决定不会变
Forget about it, guys. See you later.
不能一起去了.回头见
Professor, can I ask you something?
教授.我能问个问题吗？
You want to know why I stopped you facing that boggart, yes?
你要问我为什么阻止你 对付那博格特.对吗？
I thought it'd be obvious.
但是.我想当然地认为
I assumed it would take the shape of Lord Voldemort.
它会变成伏地魔的样子
I did think of Voldemort at first.
一开始是想到了…伏地魔 可后来想起
But then I remembered that night on the train...
那晚在火车上
- ...and the dementor. - I'm very impressed.
- 遇见摄魂怪 - 我记得
That suggests what you fear the most is fear itself.
这说明你最害怕的.是恐惧本身
This is very wise.
挺合乎情理
Before I fainted...
在我晕倒前
...I heard something.
听见了一个声音
A woman...
有个女人
...screaming.
在尖叫
Dementors force us to relive our very worst memories.
摄魂怪逼我们 想起那些最糟糕的往事
Our pain becomes their power.
我们的痛苦成了它们的力量
I think it was my mother...
是妈妈在尖叫…
...the night she was murdered.
被杀的那个晚的
The very first time I saw you, Harry, I recognized you immediately.
其实.我第一次见到你的时候就认出了你
Not by your scar, by your eyes.
不是看你的疤.而是眼睛
They're your mother, Lily's.
就像你妈妈
Yes.
是啊…
Oh, yes. I knew her.
咹.是啊.我认识她
Your mother was there for me at a time when no one else was.
我遭人冷落时.你妈妈帮助了我
Not only was she a singularly gifted witch...
她不仅是个天赋秉异的女巫
...she was also an uncommonly kind woman.
还是个极其善良的女人
She had a way of seeing the beauty in others...
她能发现别人的美 她尤其能看出那些…
...even, and most especially, when that person could not see it in themselves.
那些连别人自己都还没发现的美
And your father, James, on the other hand...
而你的父亲詹姆斯却截然不同
...he...
他…
He had a certain, shall we say, talent for trouble.
他的天赋似乎是招惹麻烦
A talent, rumor has it, he passed on to you.
这天赋…据说后来遗传给了你
You're more like them than you know, Harry.
你实在太像你的父母了
In time, you'll come to see just how much.
这总有一天你会明白的
Honeyduke's Sweetshop is brilliant, but nothing beats Zonko's Joke Shop.
蜂蜜公爵糖果店真没说的 可哪家都比不上佐科笑话店
We never got to go to the Shrieking Shack.
这次我没去成尖叫屋.那是全…
- You heard it's the most... - Haunted building in Britain. I know.
- 鬼屋 - 全英国闹鬼最厉害的 我知道
What's going on?
出了什么事儿？
Probably Neville forgot the password again.
哼.也许是纳威又把口令忘了
- Hey. - Oh, you're there.
- 嘿！ - 咹.你谁？
Let me through, please. Excuse me! I'm Head Boy!
请让我过去 对不起.我是男生会主席
Get back, all of you.
往后退.都往后退
No one is to enter this dormitory until it's been searched.
宿舍要彻底搜查.谁都不准进去
The Fat Lady! She's gone!
是胖夫人.她不见了
Serves her right. She was a terrible singer.
不见最好.她唱歌像杀猪叫
- It's not funny, Ron. - Keep calm, everyone.
- 这不好玩.罗恩 - 大家都镇静！
- Break into fours.Back to your common room. - Be quiet.The headmaster's here.
- 格兰芬多的同学回公共休息室 - 都安静.校长来了
Make way.
闪开
Come on, move.
闪开.闪开
You heard. Move!
闪开
Mr. Filch? Round up the ghosts.
费尔奇先生.请招集幽灵
Tell them to search every painting in the castle to find the Fat Lady.
叫它们搜查城堡里每一幅画.找到胖夫人
There's no need for ghosts, professor.
不需要叫幽灵了.教授
The Fat Lady's there.
胖夫人在那儿
Mind where you're going! Slow down!
嘿,嘿,嘿,走路小心点
You listen! I'm Head Boy!
慢一点.我是男生会主席
- Come back here! - Keep moving!
- 都快回来 - 回来
Dear lady, who did this to you?
嘿.这是谁干的？
Eyes like the devil, he's got, and a soul as dark as his name.
他有一双魔鬼的眼睛 灵魂就像他名字那样黑暗
It's him, headmaster. The one they all talk about.
是他.校长 大伙说的那个人.他来了
He's here, somewhere in the castle!
就在城堡里
Sirius Black!
小天狼星布莱克
Secure the castle, Mr. Filch. The rest of you, to the Great Hall.
搜查城堡.费尔奇先生.其他人都去礼堂.  好了.都接着走
I've searched the Astronomy Tower and the Owlery. There's nothing there.
我搜寻了天文塔、猫头鹰栖息地 那儿什么都没有
- Thank you. - The third floor's clear too, sir.
- 谢谢 - 三楼也没有情况
- Very good. - I've done the dungeons.
- 非常好 - 我去地窖里查过了
No sign of Black, nor anywhere else in the castle.
没发现布莱克 其他地方也没有
I didn't really expect him to linger.
我想他不会逗留不走
Remarkable feat, don't you think?
他真够本事的.你说他
To enter Hogwarts Castle on one's own...
单枪匹马进入霍格沃茨城堡
- ...completely undetected? - Quite remarkable, yes.
- 神不知鬼不觉的 - 的确
Any theories on how he managed it?
他怎么进来的.你想过？
Many. Each as unlikely as the next.
想过不少.可没有一个是可能的
You may recall...
您也许还记得
...prior to the start of term I expressed concerns...
新学期开始前.你任命卢平教授时
...about your appointment of Professor...
我曾经表示过担忧
Not a single professor inside this castle would help Sirius Black enter it.
城堡里没有一个教师会帮助小天狼星布莱克潜入
I'm quite convinced the castle is safe...
我相信城堡是安全的
...and I'm more than willing to send the students to their houses.
我还是希望能把学生们送回他们各自的学院
What about Potter? Should he be warned?
那么波特呢.该警告他吗？
Perhaps. But for now, let him sleep.
也许吧.可现在让他睡觉
For in dreams, we enter a world that's entirely our own.
睡梦中我们会进入完全属于自己的世界
Let them swim in the deepest ocean or glide over the highest cloud.
让他在最深的海洋中畅游 或者在最高的云彩上滑翔
Turn to page 394.
把书翻到第394页
Excuse me, sir. Where's Professor Lupin?
对不起.老师 卢平教授在哪儿？
That's not really your concern, is it, Potter?
这不该你操心.对吗.波特？
Suffice it to say your professor finds himself incapable of teaching...
原因很简单.你们的教授 目前身体欠佳.无法前来授课
...at the present time. Turn to page 394.
把书翻到第394页
"Werewolves"?
是狼人？
Sir, we just learned about red caps and hinkypunks.
可是老师… 我们刚学红帽子和哼皮蓬
- We're not meant to start that for weeks. - Quiet.
- 几星期后才学夜间的野兽 - 安静
When did she come in? Did you see her come in?
她几时进来的？ 你看见她进来吗？
Now, which one of you can tell me the difference...
现在.你们当中有谁能告诉我 阿尼玛格斯…
...between an Animagus and a werewolf?
和狼人的区别
No one?
没人？
- How disappointing. - Please, sir.
- 真令人失望 - 我来说
An Animagus is a wizard who elects to turn into an animal.
阿尼玛格斯可以选择变成动物
A werewolf has no choice.
而狼人却没有选择
With each full moon...
每当月圆之夜他变形时
...he no longer remembers who he is. He'd kill his best friend.
就忘了自己是谁 连最好的朋友他也会杀
The werewolf only responds to the call of its own kind.
另外… 狼人只回应他的同类发出的喊声
Thank you, Mr. Malfoy. That's the second time...
谢谢.马尔福先生
...you've spoken out of turn, Miss Granger.
这是你第二次抢着发言了.格兰杰小姐
Are you incapable of restraining yourself...
你是缺乏自制呢
...or do you take pride in being an insufferable know-it-all?
还是乐于做一个… 让人厌恶的万事通
- He's got a point, you know. - Five points from Gryffindor.
- 他说得挺有道理 - 格兰芬多扣五分
As an antidote to your ignorance, and on my desk, by Monday morning...
为了惩罚你们的无知 星期一早上每人交一篇文章
...two rolls of parchment on the werewolf, with emphasis...
两卷羊皮纸.内容是狼人 在文章中重点阐述
- ...on recognizing it. - It's Quidditch tomorrow.
- 如何识别狼人 - 老师.明天有魁地奇
Then I suggest you take extra care, Mr. Potter.
那我建议你得格外保重 波特先生
Loss of limb will not excuse you.
缺胳膊断腿照样得写文章
Page 394.
把书翻到第394页
The term "werewolf"...
狼人叫Werewolf
...is a contraction of the Anglo-Saxon word "wer"...
它由安德鲁斯·萨克逊语中的两个单词 WERE 和 WOLF 组成
...which means "man," and "wolf."
前者的意思是“男人”后者的意思是“狼”
Werewolf, man-wolf.There are several ways to become a werewolf.
狼人 有好几种方法可以变成
They include being given the power of shape-shifting...
狼人被赐予
...being bitten by a werewolf...
变形的本领、被一个狼人咬
- Go, Harry! - Go, Harry!
- 加油.哈利… - 加油.哈利…
Aresto momentum!
恩斯达麦特
- He looks a bit peaky, doesn't he? - Peaky?
- 他脸色惨白.是吗？ - 惨白？
- What do you expect? He fell over 100 feet. - Come on, Ron.
- 还能怎样.一百英尺高空摔下来 - 行了.罗恩
Let's walk you off a tower and see what you look like.
你从天文塔上摔下来.你会怎么样？
Probably a right sight better than he normally does.
也许会比他平时要好看
- How are you feeling? - Oh, brilliant.
- 感觉怎么样？ - 好极了
You gave us a right good scare.
你把我们吓坏了.伙计
- What happened? - Well, you fell off your broom.
- 怎么样了？ - 你摔下了扫帚
Really? I meant the match. Who won?
是吗？我们比赛.谁赢了？
No one blames you, Harry.
没人怪你.哈利
Dementors aren't supposed to be on the grounds. Dumbledore's furious.
摄魂怪不应该进入学校的 邓布利多大发雷霆
After he saved you, he sent them off.
他一救下了你就赶走了它们
There's something else you should know too.
另外.还有一件事你应该知道
When you fell, your broom sort of blew into the Whomping Willow, and...
你摔下来时.你的扫帚…被风吹到打人柳那儿
Well...
结果…它就
I'm sorry to hear about your broomstick.
你的扫帚坏了.真可惜
Is there no chance of fixing it?
就没办法修好它？
No.
没有
Professor, why do the dementors affect me so?
教授 摄魂怪对我的影响怎么这么大？
- I mean, more than everyone else? - Listen.
- 要比…对别人大许多 - 听着
Dementors are the foulest creatures to walk this earth.
摄魂怪是最邪恶生物之一 他们吸食每一种
They feed on every good feeling, every happy memory...
美好的情感 每一段快乐的回忆
...until a person is left with absolutely nothing but his worst experiences.
直到把人美好的东西都吸光 只剩下最糟的往事
You are not weak, Harry.
你…并不是软弱.哈利
Dementors affect you most because there are true horrors in your past.
摄魂怪对你影响最大 是因为你曾经历过真正的恐怖
Horrors your classmates can scarcely imagine.
你那些同学几乎无法想象
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
你没必要觉得羞耻
- I'm scared, professor. - I'd consider you a fool if you weren't.
- 我害怕.教授 - 你要是不害怕那倒是傻了
I need to know how to fight them. You could teach me.
我要学会跟它们斗 你可以教我
You made the one on the train go away.
火车上那个就是你赶走的
There was only one that night.
那晚只有一个
- But you made it go away. - I don't pretend to be an expert, Harry.
- 但你赶走了它 - 我可不是在假扮专家.哈利
But as the dementors seem to have developed an interest in you...
可照目前的情况来看 摄魂怪对你特别感兴趣
...perhaps I should teach you. But after the holidays.
也许我应该教你 不过得过了假期
For now, I need to rest.
现在.我需要休息
Last call for Hogsmeade! Come on, now!
准备去霍格莫德 快.同学们
- Guys, let me go. - Clever, Harry.
- 你可以… - 求你放开我
- But not clever enough. - We've got a better way.
- 可是他不够聪明 - 再说我们有更好的办法
- I'm trying to get to Hogsmeade. - We know.
- 求求你们了.我想去霍格莫德 - 我们知道
- Don't worry - We'll get you there.
- 别担心 - 我们会帮你的
- We'll show you a quicker way. - lf you pipe down.
- 我知一条捷径 - 只要你安静
- Bless him. - Let me go! Come on, guys. Don't...
- 放开我.求你们啦 - 好了.伙计们.不要...
Now, Harry. Come and join the big boys.
现在.哈利. 跟大哥们一块玩吧
What are you doing?!
你们要干嘛？
- What's this rubbish? - "What's this rubbish?" he says.
- 什么垃圾？ - 他管这叫垃圾
- It's the secret to our success. - It's a wrench giving it to you...
- 这可是我们成功的秘密 - 还舍不得给你呢
But we've decided your needs are greater than ours.
可我们认为 你比我们更需要
George, if you will.
乔治.开始吧
I solemnly swear that I am up to no good.
我郑重宣誓.我会用这来搞怪
"Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot and Prongs...
月亮脸、虫尾巴、大脚板、尖头叉子…
...are proud to present the Marauder's Map."
自豪地献上活点地图
We owe them so much.
真得感谢他们
Hang on. This is Hogwarts. And that...
等等.这是霍格沃茨 那个…
- No. Is that really... - Dumbledore.
- 哦.不 - 那这个是…
- In his study. - Pacing.
- 在他书房 - 踱步…
Does that a lot.
他老踱步
- So this map shows... - Everyone.
- 这地图能看到… - 每个人…每个人
- Where they are. - What they're doing.
- 每个人?在哪？ - 在干嘛？
- Every minute. - Every day.
- 每分钟… - 每一天
- Brilliant! Where did you get it? - From Filch's office.
- 太棒了.哪来的？ - 从费尔奇办公室偷来的
- First year. - There are seven secret passageways...out of the castle.
- 一年级时 - 好了.听着.有七条密道能走出城堡
We'd recommend this one.
我们推荐这一条…
- The One-Eyed Witch passageway. - Leads you to Honeyduke's.
- 独眼女巫通道 - 直接通往蜜蜂公爵地窖
Hurry. Filch is heading this way.
不过得快.费尔奇正过来了
And don't forget. When you're done, just give it a tap and say:
喔.哈利.别忘了 完事后.只要敲它一下.并说
"Mischief managed." Otherwise, anyone can read it.
“恶作剧完毕” 不然谁都能看它
Delicious.
味道好极了
It's meant to be the most haunted building in Britain. Did I mention that?
全英国闹鬼最厉害的鬼屋 这我提过吗？
- Twice. - Ah.
- 两遍了 - 呃
Do you want to move a bit closer?
想走得更近一些吗？
To the Shrieking Shack?
离尖叫屋近些
Actually, I'm fine here.
呃…其实我.我在这儿挺好
Well, well. Look who's here.
噢.瞧瞧.这是谁呀
You two shopping for your new dream home?
想买套新的梦之屋？
Bit grand for you, isn't it, Weasle-Bee? Don't your family sleep in one room?
太大了点吧.小蠢蛋 你家里人是睡一间房？
- Shut your mouth, Malfoy. - Not very friendly.
- 你闭嘴.马尔福 - 喔.不太友好嘛
Boys, I think it's time we teach Weasle-Bee how to respect his superiors.
伙计们.该教教韦斯莱小蠢蛋 怎么尊重长辈的
- Hope you don't mean yourself. - How dare you talk to me!
- 长辈不会是你吧 - 敢这么跟我说话
You filthy little mudblood!
你这肮脏的小泥巴种
Who is that?
是谁？
- Don't stand there! Do something! - What?
- 别傻站着.帮我 - 什么?
What's up, Malfoy? Lost your skis?
怎么的了.马尔福？滑雪板丢了？
Get out of the way!
给我闪开
Move!
走
Malfoy! Wait! Wait!
马尔福！等我！
Harry!
哈利
Bloody hell, Harry. That was not funny.
活见鬼啊.哈利 这可不好玩
Those weasels! Never told me about any Marauder's Map.
这两个坏蛋 从没跟我提过活点地图
He won't keep it. He'll turn it over to Professor McGonagall.
哈利不会留着的 他会把地图交给麦格教授
- Aren't you? - Sure. Along with his Invisibility Cloak.
- 对吗？ - 喔.当然.连同他的隐形斗篷
Look who it is. Madam Rosmerta.
喔.快瞧那个人.是罗丝莫塔女士
- Ron fancies her. - That's not true!
- 罗恩迷恋她 - 别胡说
- Professor McGonagall! - Cornelius!
- 麦格教授 - 康奈利
Allow me, minister.
请让我来.部长
- Oh, Hagrid... - Sorry about that.
- 哦.海格！ - 非常抱歉
Rosmerta, my dear. I hope business is good.
罗丝莫塔.亲爱的.希望你生意兴隆
It'd be a lot better if the Ministry wasn't sending dementors...
要是你的魔法部不让摄魂怪 每隔一天晚上来搜查.那…
- ...into my pub every other night! - We have...
- 我的生意会比现在好多了 - 我们…有个杀人凶手
- We have a killer on the loose. - Sirius Black in Hogsmeade!
- 在逃 - 小天狼星布莱克来霍格莫德
And what would bring him here?
可他为什么来？
- Harry Potter. - Harry Potter?
- 为哈利波特 - 哈利波特？
Harry!
哈利！
- No underage wizards allowed in today! - Shut the damn door!
- 嘿.未成年男巫今天不能入内 - 把该死的门关上
- So rude. - Thick heads.
- 真没礼貌 - 呆头呆脑
- Thick heads?! - How dare they!
- 呆头呆脑？ - 好大胆！
- Who are they calling thick heads? - Young whippersnappers!
- 你说谁呆头呆脑 - 有逆反的小崽仔
Nobody will come to a pub where they'll get scared out of their wits.
客人们发现店里有摄魂怪 以后谁还敢来
Professor Dumbledore doesn't want dementors around the place.
邓布利多不希望摄魂怪来干扰. 这我可保证
Tell me what this is all about.
说说.这到底怎么回事儿？
Years ago, when Harry Potter's parents realized they were marked for death...
好吧.许多年前.当哈利波特的父母 发现自己被追杀时
Remember? They hid. Few knew where they were.
就藏了起来 没多少人知道他们藏哪儿
One who did was Sirius Black. And he told You-Know-Who.
不过布莱克知道 他告诉了神秘人
Not only did Black lead him to the Potters that night...
那天晚上布莱克不光 带神秘人去了波特家
...he also killed Peter Pettigrew!
还杀他们的一个朋友小矮星彼得
- Peter Pettigrew? - Little lump of a boy.
- 小矮星彼得？ - 对.就是那个矮胖男孩
- Always trailing after Black. - I remember.
- 总跟在布莱克的身后 - 噢.想起来了
Never let James and Sirius out of his sight.
跟詹姆斯和布莱克形影不离
- What happened? - Peter tried to warn the Potters...
- 后来呢？ - 彼得想去警告波特的父母
...and might have, had he not run into an old friend, Sirius Black.
本来可以成功的.可不料撞见了个老朋友 就是布莱克
Black was vicious. He didn't kill Pettigrew.
布莱克凶狠毒辣 他不光杀死彼得
He destroyed him!
而且毁灭了他
A finger. That's all that was left. A finger. Nothing else.
一根手指.彼得只剩一根手指 没别的了
Sirius Black may not have put his hands to the Potters...
是呀.虽然不是布莱克亲手杀的
- ...but he's the reason they're dead. - He wants to finish things.
- 可正因为他.他们才会死 - 现在他想斩草除根
- I don't believe it. - That's not the worst of it.
- 这我不相信 - 这还不是最糟的
- What could be worse? - This: Sirius Black was...
- 噢.还有更更糟的？ - 听着.布莱克以前是…
...and remains to this day...
并且现在依然是…
...Harry Potter's godfather!
哈利波特的教父
Ron, look!
罗恩.快瞧
- Sorry. Excuse me, excuse me. - Merry Christmas.
- 对不起.对不起.让一下.请让一下 - 圣诞快乐
Harry, what happened?
哈利.怎么了？
He was their friend...
他是他们的朋友
...and he betrayed them.
可他出卖了他们
He was their friend!
算什么朋友！
I hope he finds me.
我希望他找到我
Because when he does, I'm gonna be ready!
他找到我.我跟他拼了
When he does, I'm gonna kill him!
他找到我.我就杀了他
Harry.
哈利？
There you are. You came.
好啊.你来了
Are you sure about this, Harry? This is very advanced magic...
你真要学吗.哈利？ 这是一种非常高深的魔法
...well beyond the Ordinary Wizarding Level.
大大高出普通魔法师的水平
I'm sure.
真要学
Well, everything's prepared.
好了.一切就绪
The spell I'm going to teach you is called the Patronus Charm.
我一会儿要教你念的咒语 叫守护神符咒
Did you ever hear of it?
听说过吗？
A Patronus is a positive force. For the wizard who conjures one...
守护神是一种正面力量 魔法师若能使用它
...it works like a shield, with the dementor feeding on it rather than him.
它就像一块盾牌.使摄魂怪改变目标. 以它为食粮
But in order for it to work, you need to think of a memory.
为使它起作用 必须回忆一段往事
Not just any memory, a very happy memory, a very powerful memory.
而且得是快乐的往事 一段强有力的回忆
Can you do this? Yes. Very well.
你能行吗？ 很好
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
Concentrate.
集中思想
Explore your past.
探索你的过去
Do you have a memory?
有回忆了吗？
Allow it to fill you up.
让它笼罩着你
Lose yourself within it.
让自己沉浸其中
Then speak the incantation, Expecto Patronum.
然后说出这条咒语 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆
- Expecto Patronum. - Very good.
- 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆 - 很好
Shall we? Wand at the ready.
开始吗？ 魔杖准备
Expecto Patronum!
[守护神咒] 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆
Expecto... Expecto...
伊克斯派克托…
Expect...
Here we go. Come on. Sit up. Deep breaths.
好了.来吧.坐起来 深呼吸
It's all right. I didn't expect you to do it the first time.
没关系 我没指望你第一次就能成功
That would have been remarkable. Here, eat this. You'll feel better.
不然也太神了 来.吃这个.会好些的
- That's one nasty dementor. - Oh, no, no, no.
- 好可怕的摄魂怪 - 嗬.不不不….
That was a boggart, Harry. A boggart.
那是一个博格特.博格特
The real thing would be worse. Much, much worse.
真正的.更可怕 比这可怕得多
As a matter of interest, what were you thinking?
可我很想知道.你在想什么？
- Which memory did you choose? - The first time I rode a broom.
- 选了哪一段回忆？ - 第一次骑扫帚
That's not good enough. Not nearly good enough.
这还不够好.实在不够好
There's another. It's not happy, exactly.
还有一段 它不算…快乐…可又
Well, it is.
很快乐…
It's the happiest I've ever felt...
那是我最快乐的记忆
- ...but it's complicated. - Is it strong?
- 可又是那么复杂 - 够强烈吗？
Then let's give it a try. You feel ready?
那我们就试试吧 准备好了吗？
Just do it.
是的
Expecto Patronum!
[守护神咒] 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆
[守护神咒] 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆…
Yes!
哈哈哈
Well done, Harry. Well done!
干得好.哈利.干得好
- I think I've had enough for today. - Yes. Sit down. Here.
- 我想今天我练够了 - 是啊.坐下.来
Eat this, it helps. It really helps.
吃这个.挺管用的
And just so you know, Harry...
我告诉你吧.哈利
...I think you'd have given your father a run for his money. And that...
你的表现已经跟你老爸 不相上下了,这已经…
...is saying something.
很了不起了
I was thinking of him.
我想的是他
And Mum.
和妈妈
Seeing their faces.
看见他们的脸
They were talking to me.
他们在跟我说话
Just talking.
就说话
That's the memory I chose.
我选了那段回忆
I don't even know if it's real.
无论是真是假
But it's the best I have.
都是最美的
- Beautiful day. - Gorgeous.
- 天气真好 - 好极了
Unless you've been ripped to pieces!
除非你被撕成碎片
835 Ripped to pieces? What are you talking about?
撕成碎片.你在说什么？
- Ronald has lost his rat. - I haven't lost anything!
- 罗恩把他的耗子给丢了 - 我可没把它丢了
- Your cat killed him! - Rubbish.
- 被你的猫吃了 - 净胡扯
Harry, you've seen the way that bloodthirsty beast of hers...
哈利.你也见过 她那只凶残的坏猫总是
...is always lurking about. And Scabbers is gone.
贼头贼脑的 我的斑斑没了
Well, maybe you should take better care of your pets!
也许你该学会怎么照顾好你的宠物
- Your cat killed him! - Did not.
- 你的猫把它吃了 - 没吃
- Did. - Didn't.
- 吃了 - 没吃
How did it go, Hagrid? The hearing?
听证会开得怎么样.海格？
Well, first off, the committee members took turns...
嗯.首先.委员们轮流谈了一下
...talking about why we were there.
为什么要召开听证会
I got up and did my piece. Said how Buckbeak...
然后我做了陈述.我说巴克比克
...was a good hippogriff, always cleaned his feathers.
是头好动物 总是清洁它的羽毛
And then Lucius Malfoy got up. Well, you can imagine.
然后.卢修斯·马尔福发言 结果可想而知
He said Buckbeak was a deadly and dangerous creature...
他说巴克比克是致命的生物
...who would kill you as soon as look at you.
是危险的.它会杀人
And then?
然后呢？
And then he asked for the worst, did old Lucius.
卢修斯要求最严厉的惩罚
- They're not sacking you! - No, I'm not sacked.
- 他们不能开除你 - 不.我没被开除
Buckbeak's been sentenced to death!
巴克比克被判处了死刑
Spiders! There's... There's spiders. Spiders. They want me to tap-dance.
有蜘蛛…有…有蜘蛛 蜘蛛要和我跳踢踏舞
- I don't wanna tap-dance! - You tell those spiders.
- 我不想跳踢踏舞 - 那你跟蜘蛛说呀
Right, yeah. Tell them. I'll tell them...
是呀.跟它们说 会说的.明天再说
（费尔奇）
（小矮星彼得）
- Peter Pettigrew? - Little lump of a boy.
- 小矮星彼得？ - 就是那个矮胖男孩
- Always trailing after Sirius Black. - Black was vicious.
- 总跟在布莱克的身后 - 布莱克凶狠毒辣
He didn't kill Pettigrew, he destroyed him!
他不光杀死了彼得 而且毁灭了他
- Put that light out! - Sorry.
- 快把灯熄了 - 对不起
（哈利波特 小矮星彼得）
（小矮星彼得）
- Watch it there, boy. - We're trying to sleep here!
- 小心点.孩子 - 别吵着我们睡觉
（斯内普）
Mischief managed. Nox.
恶作剧完毕.莫克斯
Potter.
波特
What are you doing wandering the corridors at night?
晚上你在走廊里转悠些什么？
I was sleepwalking.
我在梦游呢
How extraordinarily like your father you are, Potter.
你跟你的父亲怎么就这么像呢
He, too, was exceedingly arrogant, strutting about the castle.
波特他也是这么目中无人.趾高气扬 在城堡里逛
My dad didn't strut. And nor do I.
我爸爸没有趾高气扬 我也没有
Now, if you don't mind, I would appreciate it if you could lower your wand.
要是你不介意 麻烦你把手中的魔杖放下
Turn out your pockets.
把东西拿出来
Turn out your pockets!
快把东西…拿出来
What's this?
是什么？
- Spare bit of parchment. - Really? Open it.
- 空白羊皮纸 - 打开.打开
Reveal your secrets.
现出你的秘密
Read it.
你来念
"Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot, and Prongs...
月亮脸.虫尾巴.大脚板 尖头叉子四位先生
...offer their compliments to Professor Snape and..."
向斯内普先生问候致意 同时…
Go on.
念下去
"And request he keep his large nose out of other people's business."
同时请求他不要伸长他的大鼻子 管别人的闲事
- You insolent little... - Professor!
- 呃.好你个胆大包天的小子 - 教授先生
Well, well. Lupin.
喔…喔.卢平
Out for a little walk in the moonlight, are we?
出来散步吗？月光下漫步.是吗？
Harry, are you all right?
哈利.你没事吧？
That remains to be seen.
这就得看情况啦
I have now just confiscated a rather curious artifact.
我刚从波特这儿没收了一个 相当奇怪的小玩意
Take a look, Lupin. Supposed to be your area of expertise.
你看看吧.卢平 这应该是你的专长
- Clearly, it's full of dark magic. - I seriously doubt it, Severus.
- 很显然这上面满是黑魔法… - 嗬.我看这也未必.西弗勒斯
It looks as though it's a parchment designed to insult anyone...
这只是张特制的羊皮纸 谁要读它的内容
...who tries to read it. I suspect it's a Zonko product.
它就羞辱谁 我猜这是佐科的产品.然而
Nevertheless, I shall investigate any hidden qualities it may possess.
我应该查一下 它是否还暗藏什么特性
It is, after all, as you say, my area of expertise.
正如你说的.这是我的专长 哈利.请跟我过来
Harry, would you come with me, please? Professor, good night.
好吗？教授.晚安
Are you deaf? Put that light out!
你聋了吗？快把灯熄啦
Come in.
进来
I haven't the faintest idea how this map came to be in your possession...
我真是一点都不明白.哈利 这地图怎么会落在你的手里
...but quite frankly, I am astounded that you didn't hand it in.
可坦白地说 我十分的震惊.你居然没有上交
Did it never occur to you that this, in the hands of Sirius Black...
你想过没有这要是落到布莱克的手里
...is a map to you?
他就能通过地图找到你
- No. - No, sir.
- 没有 - 没有
Your father never set much store by the rules either.
你父亲也是个不爱遵守规定的人
But he and your mother gave their lives to save yours.
可他和你母亲为了救你 献出了他们的生命
...with a killer on the loose seems to me a poor way to repay them!
却毫无戒备地在城堡里闲逛这么做算报答他们吗？
Now, I will not cover up for you again.
现在我不会再为你掩饰了.哈利
- Do you hear me? - Yes, sir.
- 听见了吗？ - 是的
I want you to return to your dormitory and stay there.
我要你立刻回宿舍.呆在那儿
And don't take any detours. If you do, I shall know.
可别又绕远了 你要绕.我知道
Professor, just so you know, I don't think that map always works.
教授.其实这地图 并不是每次都准的
Earlier, it showed someone in the castle. Someone I know to be dead.
刚才它显示有个人在城堡 可那人已经死了
Oh, really? And who might that be?
是吗？那人是谁？
Peter Pettigrew.
小矮星彼得
That's not possible.
这绝对不可能
It's just what I saw.
反正我看见了
Good night, professor.
晚安.教授
Broaden your minds. You must look beyond.
开阔你们的思路 眼光必须放远
The art of crystal gazing is in the clearing of the Inner Eye.
水晶球占卜术的技巧在于 使你的天目变得清晰
Only then can you see. Try again.
只有这样.你们才能看见.再试一试
Now, what do we have here?
好了.这儿有什么？
Do you mind me trying?
呃.我能试试吗？
The Grim, possibly.
是…不详.有可能
My dear, from the first moment you stepped foot in my class...
亲爱的 从你踏进我课堂的那一刻起
...I sensed that you did not possess the proper spirit...
我就感觉你并不具备…卓越的法术
...for the noble art of Divination. No, you see, there.
占卜所要求的素质 你瞧这儿
You may be young in years, but your heart is as shriveled...as an old maid's,
喔.你虽然年纪小小 可惜你枯萎,就像一个老姑娘
your soul as dry as the pages of the books...
你灵魂就像这些书的纸张那么干
...to which you so desperately cleave.
这些你勤奋苦读的书
Have I said something?
我说什么了吗？
She's gone mental, Hermione has. Not that she wasn't always mental...
她真的失去理智了 赫敏她以前时常也会这样
...but now it's in the open for everyone to see.
可现在居然是在大庭广众之下
Hang on.
等等
- We better take this back. - I'm not going back.
- 这得还回去 - 我才去咧
- Fine. See you later. - See you.
- 那好.回头见 - 回头见
Harry Potter...
哈利波特…
- Professor Trelawney... - He will return tonight.
- 特里劳妮教授 - 今晚他会回来
Sorry?
什么？
Tonight, he who betrayed his friends, whose heart rots with murder...
布莱克.今晚.那出卖他朋友的人 那沦为杀人犯的人
...shall break free.
将挣脱锁链
Innocent blood shall be spilt...
无辜者的鲜血将流淌
...and servant and master shall be reunited once more.
那仆人和他的主子将再一次联起手来
I'm so sorry, dear boy. Did you say something?
真抱歉.孩子 你说什么了吗？
No.
没有
Nothing.
没什么
I can't believe they're going to kill Buckbeak. It's just too horrible.
他们居然要杀巴克比克 太可怕了
- It just got worse. - What did I say? Father said...
- 现在更糟了 - 告诉你们.我爸爸说我能留着
...I can keep the hippogriff's head. I'll donate it to the Gryffindors' room.
那怪兽的头.我想我会把它 捐给格兰芬多公共休息室
This is going to be rich.
噢.一定带劲
- Look who's here. - Come to see the show?
- 瞧.谁来了 - 哇.来看好戏的吗？
You! You foul, loathsome, evil little cockroach!
你…你这个恶心、讨厌、恶毒的小蟑螂
Hermione, no!
赫敏.别这样
He's not worth it.
这么做不值得
Malfoy, are you okay?
马尔福.你没事吧？
- Let's go. Quick. - Not a word to anyone, understood?
- 好了.我们走…等等我 - 不许跟人何人说.懂吗？
- That felt good. - Not good, brilliant.
- 感觉真好 - 不光是好.是爽歪了
Look at him. Loves the smell of the trees when the wind blows through them.
喔.你瞧它 它爱风吹过石树的气息
Why don't we just set him free?
我们干脆放了它？
They'd know it was me, and then Dumbledore...
会怀疑是我放的 会给邓布利多找麻烦
...would get into trouble. He's coming down, Dumbledore.
他一会儿也要来他说要陪我度过…
Says he wants to be with me when they...
When it happens.
度过这一刻
Great man, Dumbledore.
好人啦.邓布利多
A great man.
他是个大好人
- We'll stay with you too. - You'll do no such thing!
- 我们也陪你.海格 - 你们可别这么做
Think I want you seeing something like that? No.
这幕惨戮不会让你们看到的 不行
You just drink your tea and be off. Oh. Before you do, Ron...
喝完茶就走吧 呃.临走之前.罗恩…
Scabbers! You're alive!
斑斑.你还活着
- Keep a closer eye on your pet. - I think you owe someone an apology.
- 得看好宠物.罗恩 - 看来现在你该道歉了
Right. Next time I see Crookshanks, I'll let him know.
呃对.下次我见到克鲁克山 会赔不是的
I meant me!
是向我道歉
Blimey. What was that?
真要命.怎么回事儿？
Hagrid!
海格
Oh, crikey.
噢.天啊
No, minister. Over this way.
不.部长.就在这里边 还记得吗？
It's late. It's nearly dark. You shouldn't be here.
不早了.天快黑了 你们该走了
Someone sees you outside this time of night, you'll be in trouble.
晚上在城堡外面被人看见 就麻烦了.那是大麻烦
Particularly you, Harry. With you in a moment!
尤其是你.哈利 马上就来
Quick. Quick!
快走.快走
Hagrid.
海格
- It'll be fine. It'll be okay. - Go on, go on!
- 没事的.都会好的 - 快走.快走
- That's ling you see over there... - On the slope.
- 那叫石楠.石楠看见了吗？ - 就在那小山
- On the slope... Ah, Hagrid. - Professor Dumbledore.
- 坡上. - 海格.你好吗？
- Good evening. - Minister. Make your way through.
- 邓布利多教授 - 部长
- Have a tea, if you like. - No, Hagrid.
- 部长.快进屋吧.我们喝杯茶 - 不用.海格
- Gentlemen. - I'd like a cup of tea.
- 先生们 - 我想喝杯茶
Well, I think we should get down to our business, shall we?
好.我们言归正传了吧
Very well. It is the decision of the Committee for the Disposal...
处置危险生物委员会 现在作出决定.鹰头马兽
...of Dangerous Creatures that the hippogriff Buckbeak...
拒守法令.要成为死囚犯
...hereinafter called "the condemned", shall be executed this day at sundown.
将于今天日落时被处决
- Dear, dear... - Now, now, Hagrid. Now, come on.
- 天哪… - 好了.好了.海格.好吧
- All right. It'll be all right. - The execution shall dispatch...
- 好吧.不会有事的 - 行刑手将死囚犯进行斩首处决
What?
怎么了？
I thought I just saw...
我好像看见…
- Never mind. - Let's go!
- 算了.没什么 - 我们走
Buckbeak didn't mean no harm.
巴克比克可没有造成伤人啦
Oh, no.
哦.不
He bit me. Scabbers.
他咬我.斑斑！
Ron. Ron!
罗恩.罗恩
- Ron! - Scabbers, come back.
- 罗恩 - 斑斑.回来
Wait!
等等
- Scabbers, you bit me! - Harry, you do realize what tree this is?
- 斑斑.你咬我 - 哈利.你应该认识这棵树吧？
That's not good. Ron, run!
这可不妙.罗恩快跑
Harry, Hermione, run!
哈利.赫敏.快跑
It's the Grim!
那是不详
- Harry! - Ron! Ron, wait!
- 哈利 - 罗恩…罗恩…
Harry!
哈利
- Help! - Ron!
- 救我！- 罗恩
- Ron. Ron. - Ron!
- 罗恩.罗恩 - 罗恩！
Come on!
上
Move!
闪开
Duck!
趴下
Harry!
哈利！
- Oh, I'm sorry. - Don't worry.
- 真对不起 - 没关系
- Where do you suppose this goes? - I have a hunch.
- 你说这通往那儿？ - 我已经猜到了
I just hope I'm wrong.
但愿我错了
We're in the Shrieking Shack, aren't we?
我们在尖叫屋.对吗？
Come on.
来吧
Ron.
罗恩
- Ron. You're okay. - The dog. Where is it?
- 罗恩.没事就好 - 那狗.它在哪儿？
It's a trap. He's the dog. He's an Animagus.
哈利.他就是那狗.他是阿尼玛格斯
If you want to kill Harry, you have to kill us too!
想杀哈利.就把我们也杀了
No. Only one will die tonight.
不.今晚只会死一个人
Then it'll be you!
那就是你
Are you going to kill me, Harry?
你这是要杀我吗.哈利？
Expelliarmus!
伊克斯派里阿默斯！
Well, well, Sirius. Looking rather ragged, aren't we?
噢.好哇.布莱克 你都成这幅邋遢样了
Finally, the flesh reflects the madness within.
这外表终于配上你内心的疯狂了
Well, you'd know all about the madness within, wouldn't you?
你的内心也同样疯狂 不是吗？雷莫斯
- I found him. - I know.
- 我找到他了 - 我知道
- He's here. - I understand.
- 他在这儿 - 这我知道
- Let's kill him! - No! I trusted you!
- 杀了他 - 不.我那么信任你
And all this time, you've been his friend.
原来…你一直是布莱克的朋友
He's a werewolf! That's why he's been missing classes.
他是个狼人.所以他没法来上课
How long have you known?
你知道多久了？
- Since Professor Snape set the essay. - Well, Hermione.
- 自从写了斯内普布置的文章 - 好吧 赫敏
You are the brightest witch of your age I've ever met.
你这年纪的魔法师数你最聪明
Enough talk, Remus! Come on, let's kill him!
别再说了.雷莫斯.快点去杀了他
- Wait! - I did my waiting!
- 等等 - 我已经等够了
Twelve years of it!
等了十二年了
In Azkaban!
在阿兹卡班…
Very well. Kill him.
那好吧…杀了他
But wait one more minute. Harry has the right to know why.
可你还得再等上一分钟 他有权知道为什么
I know why.
我知道为什么
You betrayed my parents.
你出卖了我的父母
- You're the reason they're dead! - No, it wasn't him.
- 是你把他们害死的 - 不.哈利.不是他
Somebody did betray your parents...
的确有人出卖你的父母 不过是别人
...somebody who, until quite recently, I believed to be dead!
而且我最近才知道… 那个人其实并没有死
- Who was it, then? - Peter Pettigrew!
- 那人是谁？ - 彼得.小矮星
And he's in this room! Right now!
他就在屋里.就现在
Come out, come out, Peter!
出来…出来.彼得
- Come out, come out and play! - Expelliarmus!
- 来吧.快出来玩 - 伊克斯派里阿默斯
Vengeance is sweet.
噢.复仇可真有快感
How I hoped I'd be the one to catch you.
我如愿以偿.亲手抓住你
Severus...
西弗拉斯
I told Dumbledore you were helping a friend into the castle. Here's the proof.
我跟邓布利多说你在帮老朋友进入城堡.现在这就是证据
Brilliant, Snape.
好极了.斯内普
You put your keen mind to the task and come to the wrong conclusion.
这次.你那敏锐的洞察力又失误了 又得出了错误的结论
If you'll excuse us, Remus and I have business...
我们就不奉陪了 雷莫斯.我还有未了的事情要解决
- ...to attend to. - Give me a reason. I beg you!
- 给我个理由 - 让我杀了你
- Don't be a fool. - He can't help it. It's habit.
- 西弗拉斯.你别傻 - 他是傻瓜.改不了了
- Be quiet. - Be quiet yourself!
- 布莱克.你安静！ - 给我闭嘴！
You two, quarrelling like an old married couple.
好吧.听听你们俩.像老两口在拌嘴
Run along and play with your chemistry set!
我看你还是去玩过家家.配你的魔药吧
I could do it, you know.
我完全能杀了你
But why deny the dementors? They're so longing to see you.
可还是请摄魂怪代劳吧 他们一直盼着…见你呢
Do I detect a flicker of fear? Oh, yes.
你好像有点害怕了？
A Dementor's Kiss. One can only imagine what that must be like.
喔.摄魂怪的吻.想想吧 那滋味一定够受的
It's said to be nearly unbearable to witness, but I'll do my best.
有人说那场面实在是惨不忍睹 可我还是想…
Severus, please.
西弗拉斯.别这样
After you.
你先请
Expelliarmus!
伊克斯派里阿默斯
- Harry! What did you just do? - You attacked a teacher!
- 哈利.你干了什么？ - 你攻击了老师！
- Tell me about Peter. - He was at school with us.
- 告诉我彼得的事 - 以前他跟我们是同学
We thought he was our friend!
我们当他是朋友
- No. Pettigrew's dead. You killed him! - No, he didn't.
- 不.彼得死了 是你杀的 - 不.不是他
I thought so too, until you mentioned Pettigrew on the map!
我以前也以为是他 直到你说起在地图上看见了彼得
- The map was lying, then. - The map never lies!
- 那地图撒谎 - 那地图从不撒谎！
Pettigrew's alive! And he's right there!
彼得还活着.他就在那儿！
- Me?! He's mental! - Not you! Your rat!
- 我？这人疯了… - 不是你.是你的耗子！
- Scabbers has been in my family for... - Twelve years?
- 斑斑已经在我家呆了… - 十二年！
Curiously long life for a common garden rat!
一只普通耗子能活那么长吗？
- He's missing a toe, isn't he? - So what?
- 他缺一个指头.对吗？ - 那又怎么！！
- All they could find of Pettigrew was his... - Finger!
- 当时只找到彼得的… - 手指！
Dirty coward cut it off so everyone would think he was dead!
那懦夫把它割了 让大家以为他死了
- And then he transformed into a rat! - Show me.
- 然后他变形.变成了耗子 - 证明！
- Give it to him, Ron. - What are you trying to do to him?
- 快给他.罗恩 - 你要把他怎么样？
Scabbers!
斑斑.把他放了
Leave him alone! Get off him! What are you doing?
不许碰他 你要干嘛！斑斑
Remus?
雷莫斯
Sirius.
这…这是布莱克
My old friends!
我的老朋友们
Harry! Look at you. You look so much like your father.
哈利…瞧瞧你 你跟你父亲可真像.真像…
- James. We were the best of friends... - How dare you speak to Harry!
- 詹姆斯.我们曾经是最好的朋友 - 你居然敢跟哈利说话
How dare you talk about James in front of him!
你居然敢在他面前提起詹姆斯
- You sold James and Lily to Voldemort! - I didn't mean to!
- 你把詹姆斯和莉莉出卖给了伏地魔.对吗 - 其实我也不想
The Dark Lord. You have no idea the weapons he possesses!
那黑魔头.天知道他有什么武器
Ask yourself, Sirius! What would you have done?
问问你自己吧.你会怎么做？
- What would you have done? - Died, rather than betray my friends!
- 你会怎么做 - 我宁愿死！我宁愿死也不会出卖我的朋友
James wouldn't have wanted me killed!
哈利.詹姆斯不会让我死,你爸爸
Your dad would have spared me! He would have shown me mercy!
他会饶了我 他会饶了我的命
Should have realized if Voldemort didn't kill you, we would. Together!
你早该明白.彼得.伏地魔没杀你我们也会杀你.一齐动手
No!
不
- Harry, this man... - I know what he is.
- 哈利.这个人他是… - 我知道他是什么
But we'll take him to the castle.
把他带到城堡去
- Bless you, boy. Bless you! - Get off!
- 保佑你.孩子.保佑你 - 滚开
I said we'd take you to the castle.
我们把你带到城堡
After that, the dementors can have you.
然后.让摄魂怪处置你
Sorry about the bite. I reckon that twinges a bit.
抱歉.咬了你 一定有点疼吧
A bit? A bit? You almost tore my leg off!
一点？一点？ 你差点咬断我的腿
I was going for the rat.
我是想抓那耗子
Normally, I have a very sweet disposition as a dog.
通常我变成狗的时候脾气挺温顺的
More than once, James suggested that I make the change permanent.
其实.不只一次詹姆斯建议我 永远变成温顺的狗
The tail I could live with. But the fleas, they're murder.
狗尾巴我能忍受 可跳蚤.真要命
Okay.
好了
- You better go. - No. Don't worry, okay?
- 你去吧 - 别担心.没事的
It's fine. I'll stay.
我留下
You go, I'll stay.
我留下.去吧
- You okay? - I'm fine. Go.
- 没事吗？ - 没事.走吧
- That looks really painful. - So painful.
- 看来一定很疼 - 疼得要命
They might chop it.
也许…也许会锯掉
I'm sure Madam Pomfrey will fix it in a heartbeat.
庞弗雷夫人一下子就能治好
It's too late. It's ruined. It'll have to be chopped off.
完了.治不好了.一定会被锯掉
It's beautiful, isn't it?
瞧那儿多美呀？
I'll never forget the first time I walked through those doors.
我永远忘不了第一次 踏进城堡的大门
It'll be nice to do it again as a free man.
作为自由人.再次走进去 感觉一定好
That was a noble thing you did back there.
你决定不杀他很宽宏大量
He doesn't deserve it.
可他真的不配
I didn't think my dad would have wanted his best friends...
我爸爸不会希望他的好朋友 变成杀人犯的
...to become killers.
Besides, dead, the truth dies with him.
再说.真相要是活着
Alive, you're free.
你就能自由
Turn me into a flobberworm. Anything but the dementors!
求求你了.把我变成虫子也行.就是别交给摄魂怪
Ron! Haven't I been a good pet? You won't let them give me...
罗恩.我是好朋友吧.是好宠物吧 别把我交给摄魂怪.
...to the dementors, will you? I was your rat!
我是你的耗子
- Sweet, clever girl! Surely you won't... - Get away from her!
- 好姑娘.聪明姑娘.你不会让他们… - 别缠着他们.快走
I don't know if you know, Harry...
你是不是知道.哈利
...but when you were born, James and Lily made me your godfather.
你出生的时候 你父母让我做你的教父
I know.
我知道
I can understand if you choose to stay with your aunt and uncle...
要是你还想住姨父家 我也能理解
...but if you ever wanted a different home...
不过你要是想要个不同的家…
What? Come and live with you?
怎么？跟你一起住？
It's just a thought. I can understand if you don't want to.
呃.这…这是个想法 你要不愿意.我也理解
Harry!
哈利！
Remus, my old friend. Have you taken your potion tonight?
雷莫斯.我的好朋友 你今晚服过药吗？
You know the man you truly are, Remus! This heart is where you truly live! Here!
你是一个真正的人.雷莫斯 这颗心是你真正的生命.这颗心.这儿
This flesh is only flesh!
你可是有血有肉的人
Expelliarmus!
伊克斯派里阿默斯
Harry!
哈利！
Remus! Remus!
雷莫斯！
Run! Run!
快跑.快跑
- Come on. - Wait. Wait.
- 走 - 等等
- Hermione! - Bad idea. Bad idea.
- 赫敏 - 别过去…别过去…
Professor?
卢平教授？
Professor Lupin?
Nice doggy. Nice doggy!
好狗狗.好狗狗
There you are, Potter!
你在这儿.波特
Sirius!
布莱克
Come back here, Potter!
回来.波特
Sirius!
布莱克
No. Sirius!
不.布莱克
Expecto Patronum!
[守护神咒] 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆
Harry?
哈利？
I saw my dad.
我看见爸爸了
What?
什么？
He sent the dementors away.
他赶走了摄魂怪
I saw him across the lake.
他就在湖对面
Harry, they've captured Sirius.
听着.哈利.他们抓走了布莱克
Any minute the dementors are gonna perform the Kiss.
摄魂怪随时会给他一个吻
- They're gonna kill him? - No. It's worse.
- 他们要处死他？ - 不.更糟
Much worse.
比死还糟
They're going to suck out his soul.
要吸出他的灵魂
Headmaster, stop them.
校长.你必须阻止他们
- They've got the wrong man. - It's true. Sirius is innocent.
- 他们抓错人了 - 是的.校长.布莱克是清白的
- It's Scabbers who did it. - Scabbers?
- 都是斑斑干的 - 斑斑？
He's my rat, sir.
他是我的耗子
He's not really a rat. He was a rat. He was my brother Percy's rat.
他不是真的耗子 他以前是耗子.我哥哥珀西的耗子
- But then they gave him an owl... - The point is, we know the truth.
- 可后来他就有了猫头鹰… - 我们知道了真相
- Please believe us. - I do, Miss Granger.
- 请相信我们 - 我相信.格兰杰小姐
But the word of three 13-year-old wizards will convince few others.
可三个十三岁小魔法师说的话 其他人很难相信
A child's voice, however honest and true...
无论说得多诚实.如果别人不愿听
...is meaningless to those who have forgotten how to listen.
再怎么说.也都是毫无意义的
Mysterious thing, time.
时间是多么神秘
Powerful...
多么有力
...and when meddled with, dangerous.
时间被搅乱.就有危险
Sirius Black is in the topmost cell of the Dark Tower.
布莱克被关在黑塔最高的牢房里
You know the laws, Miss Granger.
你知道规定.赫敏
You must not be seen.
不能让人看见
And you would do well, I feel, to return before this last chime.
我看最好在钟敲最后一声之前赶回来
If not, the consequences are too ghastly to discuss.
不然的话.这后果将不堪设想
If you succeed tonight...
如果今晚成功了
...more than one innocent life may be spared.
就能拯救不只一条无辜的生命
Three turns should do it, I think.
转三下就可以
Oh, and by the way.
喔.我随便说一句
When in doubt, I find retracing my steps to be a wise place to begin.
要记住.拿不定主意时 照原路再走一次是明智之举
Good luck.
祝好运
What the bloody hell was that all about?
活见鬼.这是怎么回事啊？
Sorry, Ron, but seeing as you can't walk...
对不起.罗恩.你好好养伤吧
What just happened?
怎么回事？
- Where's Ron? - 7:30.
- 罗恩呢？ - 七点半
Where were we at 7:30?
七点半时.我们在哪儿？
I don't know. Going to Hagrid's?
正在去海格的小屋吧
Come on. And we can't be seen.
快走.不能被看见
Hermione!
赫敏
Hermione! Hermione, wait.
赫敏…赫敏.等等
Hermione, will you please tell me what it is we're doing?
赫敏.拜托.告诉我这是在干什么？
You foul, loathsome, evil little cockroach!
你这个恶心、讨厌、恶毒的小蟑螂
That's us.
那是我们耶
Hermione, no! He's not worth it.
赫敏.别这样 这么做不值得
This is not normal.
这真是太离谱了
This is a Time-Turner, Harry.
这是时间转换器.哈利
McGonagall gave it to me first term.
第一学期.麦格教授给我的
This is how I've been getting to my lessons all year.
所以一学年来.我能同时上几门课
- You mean we've gone back in time? - Yes.
- 我们回到了以前 - 是的
Dumbledore obviously wanted us to return to this moment.
显然邓布利多就是要我们回到这一刻
Clearly, something happened he wants us to change.
他是要我们改变已经发生的事
Good punch.
这一拳很漂亮
Thanks.
谢谢
Malfoy's coming.
马尔福来了
- Run. - Not a word to anyone, understood?
- 不许跟人何人说.懂吗？ - 好吧
I'm gonna get that jumped-up mudblood! Mark my words.
我会收拾那狂妄的泥巴种.等着吧
- That felt good. - Not good, brilliant.
- 感觉真好 - 不光是好.是爽歪了
Come on. We should be at Hagrid's.
走吧.海格的小屋
Look. Buckbeak's still alive.
快瞧.巴克比克还活着
Of course.
这就对了
Remember what Dumbledore said?
记得邓布利多怎么说的?
If we succeed, more than one innocent life could be spared.
如果成功了 能拯救不只一条无辜的生命
Let's go.
走
Here they come. I'd better hurry.
他们来了 得赶快去
Fudge has to see Buckbeak before we steal him.
让福吉看到巴克比克.我们再偷
Otherwise, he'll think Hagrid set him free.
不然他会怀疑是海格
Scabbers, you're alive!
斑斑.你还活着
- Keep a closer eye on your pet. - That's Pettigrew.
- 得看好宠物… - 那是彼得
- Harry, you can't. - He betrayed my parents.
- 哈利.不能去 - 那家伙出卖了我父母.你要我
- You don't expect me to sit here. - Yes, and you must!
- 在这儿干坐着？ - 是的.必须这么做
Harry, you're in Hagrid's hut now.
哈利.当时你在海格的小屋
If you go bursting in, you'll think you've gone mad.
现在闯进去 你会以为自己疯了
Awful things happen to wizards who meddle with time.
胡乱改变过去.下场会很惨的
We can't be seen.
不能让人看见
Fudge is coming.
福吉来了
And we aren't leaving?
当时该走了吗？
Why aren't we leaving?
当时为什么不走？
Are you mad?
你疯了吗？
That hurt.
那很疼
Sorry.
对不起
We're coming out the back door. Go!
我们从后门出来了.走
Is that really what my hair looks like from the back?
我的头发从后面看真是这样吗？
What?
怎么了？
I thought I just saw...
我好像看见…
- Never mind. - Let's go.
- 算了.没事儿 - 我们走
Okay, go, Harry. Go!
好.走.快走
Get away. Get off.
走开
Minister, I really think I should sign as well.
呃.部长.我想我用不着签名了
Yes, very well. Perhaps it would be...
怎么啦？
Okay, Buckbeak. Come quickly. Come with us now. Come on.
好了.巴克比克.快来我们快点走.快走
Keep trying. Come on. Quickly.
快点.快拉.快点
Buckbeak. Okay? Quickly. Hurry up. Okay?
快点.快走吧
- Your name only. - It's such a very long name...
- 名字签在横线上 - 我的名字很长
Hurry up now, Buckbeak, okay?
快点.巴克比克
Come on. Come on, Buckbeak.
Come and get the nice dead ferret.
快过来.很好吃啊
- Come on. It's here. Come on, Beaky. - Here we are, minister. Follow me.
- 这儿.快点.巴克比克 - 这儿.部长.跟我来
- Now, look there. - Where?
- 瞧那儿.看见吗？ - 哪儿？
- Look beyond the rocks. - What am I supposed to see?
- 瞧岩石后面 - 你这是要我看什么？
Professor Dippet had that ling planted when he was headmaster.
利皮教授做校长那会儿 种了那株石楠
- Oh, yes. Indeed, indeed. - And all the strawberries.
- 哦.是的…没错.没错 - 还有那些草莓
- Come on, Buckbeak. Come on. - I see no strawberries.
- 快点.巴克比克.快点 - 我没见到草莓
- Over there. - Where?
- 就在那儿 - 哪里?
- Over there. - This way.
- 就在那儿 - 瞧
- Let's get this over, please. - All right.
- 好的.先把正事干完吧 - 好吧
But where is it?
它哪儿去了？
I saw the beast, just now.
我刚才还看见它呢？
- Not a moment ago! - How extraordinary.
- 一会儿就不见了 - 实在是奇怪
Buckbeak.
巴克比克？
Come now, Dumbledore. Someone's obviously released him.
糟糕.邓布利多 是有人把它放了
- Hagrid? - Buckbeak.
- 海格？ - 我发誓.不是我干的
I don't think the minister's suggesting you had anything to do with this.
我想部长并没说这事跟你有关
How could you? You've been with us all the time.
是你呢 你一直跟我们在一起
- Right. - Well, well...
- 对啊 - 那好.那好
We must search the grounds.
得搜查整个场地
Well, search the skies, if you must, minister.
有必要的话搜一下天空吧.部长
Meanwhile, I'd like a nice cup of tea or a large brandy.
现在,我想品一杯好茶或者一大杯白兰地
Oh, executioner, your services are no longer required.
喔.行刑手 这儿不再需要你服务了
Thank you.
谢谢
You'll find no small glasses in this house, professor.
我屋子里可没有小杯子,教授
- Come on. - This way.
- 快点 - 这边
This way, now.
快来
- Now what? - We save Sirius.
- 现在呢？ - 救布莱克
- How? - No idea.
- 怎么救？ - 不知道
- Look. It's Lupin. - Immobulus!
- 里劳克拉斯！ - 瞧.是卢平
And Snape's coming.
接着是斯内普
And now we wait.
现在我们等着
- At least someone's enjoying himself. - Yeah.
- 至少有人乐在其中 - 是呀
- Hermione? - Yeah?
- 赫敏？ - 什么？
Before, down by the lake, when I was with Sirius...
先前…在湖边跟布莱克一起时
...I did see someone.
我是看到一个人
That someone made the dementors go away.
正是那个人赶走了摄魂怪
With a Patronus.
用守护神符咒
I heard Snape telling Dumbledore.
斯内普、邓布利多说过
According to him...
听他们的意思…
...only a really powerful wizard could have conjured it.
只有真正强大的魔法师才能施那个咒
It was my dad.
那是我爸爸
My dad conjured the Patronus.
那个施魔咒的是我爸爸
- Harry, but your dad's... - Dead. I know.
- 可你爸爸已经… - 死了.我知道
I'm just telling you what I saw.
可我的确看见了
Here we come.
我们来了
You see Sirius talking to me there?
看见布莱克跟我说话吗？
- He's asking me to come live with him. - That's great.
- 他是要我跟他一起住 - 太棒了
When we free him, I'll never have to go back to the Dursleys'.
等放了他.我就不用再回德思礼家了
It'll just be me and him.
只有我和他
We could live in the country...
可以住在乡村
...someplace you can see the sky.
可以看辽阔的天空
He'll like that after all those years in Azkaban.
被关了这么多年 他渴望自由
Harry!
哈利！
Run!
快跑！
Let's go.
我们走
- What are you doing? - Saving your life.
- 你在干嘛？ - 救你的命啊
Thanks.
谢谢
- Great. Now he's coming for us. - Yeah, I didn't think about that. Run!
- 他冲我们来了 - 这我没料到.跑
That was so scary.
真是太可怕了
Poor Professor Lupin's having a really tough night.
可怜的卢平一晚上真够呛
Sirius. Come on!
布莱克.快走
- This is horrible. - Don't worry.
- 这可真恐怖 - 别担心
My dad will come. He'll conjure the Patronus.
我爸爸会来的.他会施守护神咒
Any minute now.
他就要来了
Right there. You'll see.
就在那儿.你会看见的
Harry, listen to me. No one's coming.
哈利.听我说.没人会来
Don't worry, he will. He will come.
别担心.他会来的.一定会来
- Sirius. - You're dying...
- 布莱克 - 你快死了…
...both of you.
布莱克也是
Harry!
哈利！
Expecto Patronum!
[守护神咒] 伊克斯派克托 派丘能姆
You were right, Hermione.
你说得没对.赫敏
It wasn't my dad I saw earlier. It was me!
先前看到的不是我爸爸.是我
I saw myself conjuring the Patronus before.
我在使守护神咒.这次我知道
I knew I could do it this time because...
我能行.是因为…
...well, I had already done it.
我成功过
- Does that make sense? - No.
- 这说得通吗？ - 不
But I don't like flying!
我不喜欢飞
Bombarda!
冻德巴道
I'll be forever grateful for this...
救命之恩.永生难忘
...to both of you.
感谢你们
- I want to go with you. - One day, perhaps.
- 我想跟你走 - 以后吧
For some time, my life will be too unpredictable.
接下来这段时间我会漂泊不定
And besides...
再说…
- ...you're meant to be here. - But you're innocent.
- 你该留在这儿 - 可…你是清白的
And you know it.
这一点你知道…
And for now, that will do.
你知道就足够啦
I expect you're tired of hearing this...
有句话你得听腻味了
...but you look so like your father.
你长得可真像你爸爸
Except your eyes.
除了你的眼睛
- You have... - My mother's eyes.
- 你的… - 眼睛像我妈妈
It's cruel that I spent so much time with James and Lily, and you so little.
这挺惨酷.我跟你父母相处了 那么久,你却没这个福
But know this:
但你记住
The ones that love us never really leave us.
爱我们的人永远不会离开我们
And you can always find them...
永远能找到的
...in here.
在这儿
You really are the brightest witch of your age.
你这年龄的女魔法师里.你最聪明
We have to go.
我们得走了
- Well? - He's free. We did it.
- 怎么？ - 他自由了.我们做到了
Did what?
做到什么？
Good night.
晚安
How did you get there?
怎么蹦那儿去了？
I was talking to you there. And now you're there.
说话的时候在这儿 可现在在那儿？
- What's he talking about, Harry? - I don't know.
- 他在说什么啊？ - 不知道
Honestly, Ron. How can somebody be in two places at once?
一个人怎么可能同时在两个地方呢
Hello, Harry.
你好.哈利
I saw you coming.
我看见你来了
I've looked worse, believe me.
我这样子还不算是最糟的
- You've been sacked. - No.
- 你被开除了？ - 不
No. I resigned, actually.
不.其实我…辞职
Resigned? Why?
辞职？为什么？
Well, it seems that somebody let slip the nature of my condition.
有人说漏了嘴 无意中把我的情况抖了出去
This time tomorrow, the owls will start arriving and parents will not want...
明天这时候.猫头鹰们就要捎信来了 家长们不会想要…
...well, someone like me teaching their children.
我这样的人.教他们的孩子
- But Dumbledore... - He has already...
- 可邓布利多… - 邓布利多为我担的风险
...risked enough on my behalf.
已经够多了
Besides, people like me are...
再说.像我这样的人…
Well, let's just say that I'm used to it by now.
算了.反正我都已经习以为常了
Why do you look so miserable, Harry?
干嘛哭丧着脸.哈利
None of it made any difference.
一切都是徒劳
- Pettigrew escaped. - Didn't make any difference?
- 彼得逃走了 - 一切都是徒劳？我看是扭转
It made all the difference in the world. You uncovered the truth.
乾坤了.你帮忙揭露 了真相.拯救了一个
You saved an innocent man from a terrible fate.
清白的人免遭厄运
It made a great deal of difference.
怎么能说是徒劳呢？
If I am proud of anything...
让我觉得骄傲的是
...it is of how much you have learned this year.
这学年你学会了很多
Now, since I am no longer your teacher...
既然我不再是你的老师了
...I feel no guilt whatsoever about giving this back to you.
那我可以无所顾忌地把这还给你
So now I'll say goodbye, Harry.
现在该说再见了.哈利
I feel sure we'll meet again sometime.
我们一定会后会有期
Until then...
不过现在…
...mischief managed.
恶作剧完毕
（活点地图）
Stand back, I said! Or I'll take it upstairs if you don't settle.
不许乱摸 不乖些.我就拿楼上去
Harry.
哈利
Wherever did you get it?
这里是从哪弄来的？
Can I have a go, Harry? After you, of course.
我能骑吗.哈利？ 等你骑过之后
- What are you talking about? - Quiet.
- 你们在说什么呀？ - 都安静
Let the man through. I didn't mean to open it, Harry.
给老大让路 我…我其实没想打开的
It was badly wrapped. They made me do it.
可它包得很不好 他们叫我打开的
Did not.
别胡说
- It's a Firebolt. - It's the fastest broom in the world.
- 这是火努箭 - 最快的飞天扫帚
For me?
给我的？
- But who sent it? - No one knows.
- 谁送的？ - 没人知道
This came with it.
还有这个
- Go on, Harry! - Yeah, let's see.
- 骑上去让我们看看 - 这下我们一定能赢魁地奇杯
How fast is it, Harry?
它能飞多快.哈利？
Lumos.
鼓德尤莫斯
I solemnly swear that I am up to no good.
我郑重宣誓.我会用这个来搞怪